# Colton Acosta

404.430.1346 • cacost12@asu.edu • US Citizen • linkedin.com/in/colton-acosta/

#### **SUMMARY**

Junior aerospace engineering student with leadership experience in team-based, results-oriented projects including work in hardware-software interfacing, specification development, computer-aided modeling, and systems integration. Interests include control theory, signal processing, avionics, and propulsion. Open to relocation.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### B.S.E, Aerospace Engineering; Autonomous Vehicle Systems

Graduating May 2022

Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ

4.00 GPA

Barrett, The Honors College

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Presentation and Organization: Microsoft Office, IAT<sub>E</sub>X

Design and Modeling: MATLAB, SOLIDWORKS, LabVIEW

Programming: Python, C/C++, Linux (git, vim, gcc), R

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Liquid Propulsion Avionics Lead, Sun Devil Rocketry

August 2019-Present

- Leading efforts on the development of an avionics system for a liquid bi-propellant engine with over twenty hardware components including valves, sensors, and controllers
- Interfacing temperature, pressure, thrust, and flow measurements with a custom Python program
- Conducting trade studies on electronic actuators and orifice flow meters to develop specification requirements using MATLAB for multivariate trade-off analyses and physical modeling
- Built a signal amplifier to boost sensor outputs to measurable ranges resulting in savings upwards of \$200
- Reported project progress in published AIAA Propulsion and Energy conference paper
- Wrote a development plan for the 2020-2021 academic year consisting of 42 deliverables to cultivate a results-oriented work environment and to delegate workloads among new talent

# 5280 Team Member, Sun Devil Rocketry

Fall 2018-Spring 2019

- Collaborated with a group of 12 students to launch an amateur rocket to an altitude of 5280 feet
- Determined build specifications, apogee altitude, and static margin with OpenRocket software
- Constructed rocket with phenolic tubing wrapped with epoxied fiberglass fabric and laser-cut fins
- Pragmatically adjusted final build to mitigate static margin error, allowing rocket to be launched on time
- Used a microcontroller breakout board with internal altimeter for parachute deployment

# ACADEMIC PROJECTS

# Team Lead, Airfoil Statistics Project

Spring 2020

- Lead a group of seven students to complete a semester long project by devising a project plan, delegating workloads, setting timelines, and scheduling team meetings
- Collected computational aerodynamic data with Ansys for airflow over a wing section with configurable design specifications created with SOLIDWORKS from a NACA 2412 airfoil parameterization
- Used the R language to analyze data with an Analysis of Variance test and to compute significance-based regression models for wing section lift and drag response to chord length, angle of attack, and sweep angle

# Honors Student, Trans-lunar Injection Simulation

Spring 2019

- Simulated a free-return, trans-lunar injection orbital trajectory in MATLAB with an animated solution
- Calculated the trajectory by solving the two-body problem using a numerical differential equation solver built from scratch with Apollo 11 low earth orbit initial conditions